JOSHUA MCCARTNEY

SENIOR ART DIRECTOR

2 VALMAR ROAD, FLAT 3, LONDON, SE5 9NG

+44 7949771957

ME@JOSHUAMCCARTNEY.COM

W W W . J O S H U A M C C A R T N E Y . C O M

PROFILE

Working professionally in the digital industry for 12 years, I have moved up from Junior Designer to Senior Art Director of Ralph in the London office, on to taking charge of the New York and Los Angeles office's entire design output as Head Of Visual. Over this time I have gained valuable experience:

- Art direction and creative control over design department
- Responsibility over the visual output of Ralph London, New York and Los Angeles offices
- Full management of design teams including recruitment, mentoring and support
- Creating, presenting and delivering pitch creative to clients
- Maintaining client relationships
- Designing, creating and maintaining solid, intuitive user experiences
- Facilitating team development through education, literature and workshops

I am a thoughtful and passionate creative. I thrive on working closely in teams, guiding the deliverance of the best quality work always keeping an eye on future trends.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Art Director, Ralph, London - 2018 - Present

Moving back from New York, in a senior role at Ralph London, I am working with and educating the team with the knowledge I have gained working with our larger American digital broadcast clients - Netflix, Facebook Watch, Amazon Prime amongst others.

Head Of Visual, Ralph, New York - 2014 - 2018

Working closely with our CD/CEO, I have been active in helping increase the quality and output of the NY office by hiring new designers, promoting and guiding individuals in the design team as well as maintaining client relationships. While being firmly involved in the design process myself, cultivating our award winning design team is my objective.

Design Director, Ralph, New York - 2012 - 2014

Utilising skills learned in my previous positions, I have been able to work myself up to management level - liaising with clients and managing the design team through all studio and pitch work. During this time I have had the opportunity to focus on cross device cutting edge responsive HTML5 / CSS3, mobile app and immersive personalised video campaign design.

Junior / Mid-Weight Designer, Ralph, London, UK - 2007 - 2012

I moved from Liverpool to London to join Ralph as a Junior Designer. Over this period I worked up from a Junior position to Mid-Weight Designer. I have been able to give direction to Junior Designers and Developers, conceptualise and create award winning work.

EDUCATION

Birkenhead Sixth Form College, UK - 1997-1999 GNVQ Art & Design (Distinction)

SKILLS

Art Direction, team management, design production, campaign creative and ideas, direction and quality control of the design team, UI/UX and wireframe creation for user flow and documentation, pitch creative (brain storming, mock-ups etc.), client relations (presentations, calls, email correspondence), animation (After Effects, Element 3D and other motion graphics), print design (design through to delivery of print), photography, video editing, directing, audio design and audio production.